lineage2.com 2018-05-05

# Privacy Policy

Your privacy is important to NCSOFT. Maintaining the trust of our users is key to the success of our business and this Privacy Policy is intended to inform you of our information collection and use while visiting our website and playing NCSOFT games.  For your information and for the purposes of this Privacy Policy, NC Interactive, LLC (“NCSOFT”) is the data controller and your Personal Information (as defined below) may be handled and otherwise processed by NC Interactive, LLC and NCSOFT Europe Limited in providing various NCSOFT services to you.

This Privacy Policy discloses the privacy practices for:

It also includes any other sites and services related to NCSOFT (collectively, the "Sites").

From time to time, we may add new Sites that may not be set forth in the prior sentence, but they will provide a link to this Privacy Policy and will be governed by its terms.

This Privacy Policy will provide you with information on our policies regarding:

  1. Collection of Personal Information
  2. Who collects the Personal Information
  3. How the Personal Information is used
  4. Privacy protections for children
  5. The choices available to users regarding collection, use and distribution of the Personal Information
  6. How you can correct any inaccuracies in regard to your Personal Information
  7. What kind of security procedures we use to protect the loss, misuse, or alteration of your Personal Information under our control
  8. Information for people in the European Union
  9. Notice of changes to the Privacy Policy

_Personal Information_. "Personal Information" is information that would allow someone to identify or contact you, including, for example, your full name, address, telephone number, or email address. Personal Information does not include aggregated information that, by itself, does not permit the identification of individual persons (like statistics about how many persons visited our web site last month, or how many visitors are male and how many are female).

_Acceptance.  _This Privacy Policy is a part of our Website Terms of Use and by using the Sites you agree to be bound by its terms and conditions.  This Privacy Policy only addresses activities from our servers. Other sites (including those to which we may link) and other service providers may have their own privacy policies, which we do not control, and thus are not addressed or controlled by this policy. Please note that NC Interactive is not based within the European Union and has its place of business in the United States of America and that by agreeing to this Privacy Policy, you are consenting to the transfer of your Personal Information to the United States of America.

**1\. Collection of Personal Information**

You provide certain Personal Information to us when you:

  1. register to use the services
  2. register for contests or giveaways
  3. complete questionnaires
  4. order products and services from us
  5. send email messages, submit forms or send other information to us
  6. log-in to the Sites using a third party service (e.g., Facebook)

When you communicate within any game or any other communication feature within any of our Sites (e.g. live chat, instant message services and the like), even "privately" to another person, you do so with the understanding that those communications go through our servers, can be monitored by us, you have no expectation of privacy in any of those communications and, accordingly, you expressly consent to monitoring of communications (including technical support and customer service communications) that you send and receive.

**Logging of Chats or Messaging Features**

NCSOFT will store all communication exchanged between you and any other person while using any game served by NCSOFT. This not only includes "public" chats but also includes all messages exchanged in private chats; "party," "guild," or "alliance" chats; as well as all messages sent using the mail system in our game (herein collectively referred to as "Communication Data").

The Communication Data will be stored by NCSOFT on its own servers which are maintained only by internal IT staff of NCSOFT. Staff members have been advised not to access the Communication Data unless expressly requested by NCSOFT's executive management.

Customer Support, including 3rd party support contractors and a subset of software development staff may access the Communication Data, but only from within the local area network of NCSOFT or via a secure, encrypted tunnel from an approved site. Every access to the Communication Data is logged and such log files are controlled on a regular basis for compliance with the rules of the data processing agreement. Any outside access is restricted by technical measures. Physical access to the servers is restricted by physical access controls and identification requirements. Customer Support staff of NCSOFT have been instructed to access the Communication Data only upon the receipt of a Customer Support request relating to that specific set of Communication Data. Software development staff of NCSOFT has been instructed to access the Communication Data only when necessary to perform development and debugging tasks related to the collection, querying, and parsing of Communication Data for Customer Support related tools. Customer Support and software development staff are instructed not to access Communication Data under any other circumstances. Communication Data is not transferred to any third party under any circumstances unless such disclosure is legally required by law enforcement authorities or by a court order of a US court or a court of a member state of the European Union.

The Communication Data is stored as long as it is required to provide customer support. Unless any Communication Data is used to aid a customer's support request, or is used to investigate a breach of the User Agreement (or any other agreement) between you and NCSOFT or is the subject of a request from law enforcement authorities, all Communication Data is deleted after two months. Mail sent to other players outside of the control of NCSOFT may be stored longer depending on the time the recipient deletes the mail from his inbox.

Should you have any questions in relation to the logging of chats or messaging features you may contact NCSOFT at support@ncsoft.com.

**Use of Email Address**

Your email address will be used to contact you regarding specific issues related to your account(s). You may also receive special notices and offers for products and services offered by NCS. You will be given the opportunity to "opt out" of any mailings which do not include critical information regarding your active game account(s).

Please see "Sweepstakes, Contests and Promotions, and Related Third Party Services" below for specific information on how your Personal Information may be used by third parties in those special cases.

**Payment Method**

You may be asked to submit Personal Information depending on the payment method you choose when accessing, purchasing or subscribing to one of our products or services. For example, if you choose to pay for NCSOFT products or services by credit card, you will be required to provide us or a third party the name of your credit card issuer, credit card number, billing address, CVV number, and expiration date.

If you choose to pay for NCSOFT products or services and/or the services NCSOFT performs on behalf of its affiliates by using, without limitation, check, PayPal, SMS, paysafecard, Game Time Cards, or ELV, you will be required to provide us or a third party with applicable Personal Information in order to permit us or a third party to process such payment.

**Non-personal Information**

In addition to the login information, we will automatically collect certain non-personal information about your use of our Sites and services. We might collect, among other things, information concerning the type of Internet browser, computer, or computer operating system you are using, the domain name of your Internet service provider, your "click path" through the Sites, and the web site or advertisement that was linked to or from the Sites when you visited. To do this, we may use cookies and other technology (see below).

Your visits to our Sites, and information provided through these technologies, will be anonymous unless you provide us with Personal Information or have provided such information in the past. For example, if you've created a membership account, your account information (including name, email address, and billing and shipping information) may be linked to the items you purchased at our online store (i.e., purchase order history).

This information is only used for our internal purposes (such as to improve the Site or to customize content).

**Cookies and Related Technologies**

We and our third party advertising and analytics providers use a feature of your browser called a "cookie" to assign a unique number that automatically identifies your computer when you visit our Sites. A cookie is a piece of text-only data stored on your hard drive. Some cookies remain on your computer until you delete them others, like session ID cookies, expire when you close your browser.  By setting a cookie on our Sites, you would not have to log in a password more than once, thereby saving time while on our Sites.

We and our third party advertising and analytics providers use tracking identifiers (such as Clear GIFs, pixels, web beacons) to track the online movements of web users. Unlike cookies, tracking identifiers are tiny graphics that are embedded invisibly on web pages or in HTML-based emails. We and our third party providers may place tracking identifiers on our Sites that track what other websites you visit (both before and after visiting the Sites) to obtain information about the effectiveness of advertisements on our Sites as well as on other websites and to help us improve our business and our Sites.

You may set your browser setting to attempt to reject the cookies and tracking identifiers and you may still use our Sites. The only drawback to this is that you may be limited in some areas of our Sites, or may have to enter passwords or identifying information more than once.

We do not control the use of cookies or tracking identifiers by third parties. See the section on “Third Party Advertisers and Analytics Providers” below and review the privacy policies of each of each third party provider for more information on their use of cookies and tracking identifiers and how they may track users.

**Logging into the Sites through Third Party Services**

We may provide the option for you to log in to our Sites and access services using your credentials ( _e.g_., user name and password) from a third party service ( _e.g._ , Facebook).  If you choose to login to our Sites using this feature, we may obtain information about you (including Personal Information) from the third party service (including your email address, profile information,  and other information you have provided to the third party service).  Our use of Personal Information provided to us by those third parties is governed by this Privacy Policy.  We do not control the information that third parties collect or their use of that information.  You should review the third parties' privacy policies for more information regarding their collection, use and sharing of information, including what information they may disclose to us if you use their service credentials to login to our Sites.

**Third Party**   **Advertisers and Analytics Providers**

We work with third party advertising and analytics providers, such as Google Analytics, for collecting information about users and their usage of our Sites and targeting advertisements on our Sites.  We may share non-personal information about your use of our Sites with those third party providers.  The third party providers use cookies and tracking identifiers (such as Clear GIFs, pixels, web beacons) in order to collect demographic and interest-level information and usage information from users that visit our Sites, including information about the pages where users enter and exit the Sites and what pages and advertisements users view and visit on the Sites. Cookies and tracking identifiers allow advertisers and analytics providers to recognize a user when a user visits our Sites, when a user visits other websites, what ads have been displayed to a browser, and when a user accesses an advertiser’s site. Our third party providers use the information they collect from the Sites and other websites to profile users in order to display relevant advertising and to share with us and other web site operators information about users including, but not limited to, age range, gender, geographic regions, general interest and details about devices used to visit websites and purchase items. We do not link information we receive from our third party providers with Personal Information.

Specifically, with respect to Google Analytics, we use the following advertising features: Remarketing with Google Analytics, Google Analytics Demographics and Interest Reporting, Google Display Network Impression Reporting, Google Cookie Matching Service, Google Double Click Ads Exchange, and AdWords features for remarketing, in-market audiences, affinity audiences, custom affinity audiences, similar audiences, and demographic and location targeting. We use these advertising features to improve our marketing campaign targeting.   Google’s collection and use of information is subject to Google’s Privacy Policy (<http://www.google.com/policies/privacy/>) and specific information regarding how Google uses of information from Google Analytics is available at How Google Uses Data When You Use Our Partners' Sites or Apps (<http://www.google.com/policies/privacy/partners/>) and Types of Cookies Used by Google (http://www.google.com/policies/technologies/types/).  If you would like to opt out of Google Analytics tracking, please visit one of the following links: Google Ads Settings (<http://www.google.com/settings/ads>), the Google Analytics Opt-out Browser Add-on (<https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout/>), or the NAI’s consumer opt-out (http://www.networkadvertising.org/choices/).

The privacy policies of third parties we work with for advertising purposes are available on their websites. These privacy policies will provide more information on those third parties’ use of cookies and tracking identifiers and whether they permit you to opt out of the use of cookies for interest-based advertising. For additional information regarding opting out of some third-party vendors' use of cookies for interest-based advertising, visit[ http://www.aboutads.info](http://www.aboutads.info/).

**Sweepstakes, Contests and Promotions, and Related Third Party Services**

To participate in some of our sweepstakes, contests, surveys, and other promotions, you may be asked to provide additional Personal Information such as your mailing address. In each such case, no new Personal Information will be collected from you without your consent. This information may be collected by NCSOFT or by third parties such as co-sponsors or vendors for the promotion.

Our use of any such information will be governed by this Privacy Policy. The names of third parties such as co-sponsors (other than vendors hired by NCSOFT to conduct, administer, and execute a promotion on behalf of NCSOFT) will be disclosed to you when you are asked to sign up for the promotion. You should review such third parties' privacy policies to see how they may use any information that they collect.

Certain NCSOFT services, sweepstakes and/or contests, may be provided to you in conjunction with a third party. During the registration process for any such sweepstakes, contests, surveys, and other promotions or service(s) related to such games, you may be notified that such third party wishes access to some of your Personal Information.

In such a situation, you will be given an opportunity to decline to share that information with that third party before any such information is shared. If you decline to share such information with the relevant third party, you may not be able to participate in such sweepstakes, contests, surveys, and other promotions or service(s) for that game.

As described in the registration process, a third party's use of the shared Personal Information will be governed by any privacy policy that company may have in place and our use of such information shall, of course, be governed by the terms of this Privacy Policy.

**Online Communications, Games**

When you play any of the games offered and/or served by NCSOFT, or use any of the communication features on the Sites, your IP address (the Internet protocol address from which you access any of the above) may be stored in our records.

When any game is updated or "patched," our patch routine may check your computer to see that you have the most recent version of game-specific files.

When you log into one of our online games, your system specifications (such as OS, RAM, video card, monitor, system configuration, etc.) may be reviewed/recorded by us for the purposes of analyzing and optimizing your game experience and in order to provide you with customer service.

**2\. Who collects the Personal Information**

NCSOFT owns and operates the Sites, and is the company that collects Personal Information on our site. Our mailing address is NC Interactive, LLC, 3180-138th Avenue SE, Suite 500, Bellevue, WA 98005, USA and our customer service email address is support@ncsoft.com.

**3\. How the Personal Information is used**

Personal Information which we collect for a particular purpose will only be saved and used for that purpose, unless you have agreed to allow us to use it for some other purpose, as described in this Privacy Policy.

For example, if you make a purchase from our online store, and unless you have given us permission to do otherwise, we will only collect and save the Personal Information you provided to us, including your billing and delivery information, in order to:

  1. Complete the sale
  2. Comply with tax and other applicable statutes
  3. Maintain accurate business and financial records (in accordance with accepted standards)
  4. Assist with customer service and returns

When you have provided Personal Information to us for a particular purpose, we may disclose your information to other companies that we have engaged to assist us in fulfilling your request. This may include, but is not limited to, fulfillment houses, billing services, transaction managers, credit verification services, and other third-party service providers.

We may also disclose any of your Personal Information to law enforcement or other appropriate third parties in connection with criminal investigations, investigation of fraud, infringement of intellectual property rights, or other suspected illegal activities, or as otherwise may be required by applicable law, or, as we deem necessary in our sole discretion, in order to protect the legitimate legal and business interests of NCSOFT.

We may use the information we collect from you for the purpose of providing you with technical support, customer service, and account maintenance. We use the information we collect to learn what you like, tailor your experience accordingly, and to improve our Sites and our other products. We send email to our members who want to receive email from us.

However, if you don't want to receive email from us, you can "opt out" of receiving it at the time you register as a member on our Sites or each time we request information from you. If you change your mind and wish to stop receiving email from us, you may also choose to opt out by following the steps described in each such email.

Except as described in this policy, we will not give any of your Personal Information to any third party without your express approval, and the only Personal Information we will ask you if you want us to share with third parties is your name, your mailing address and email address.

If you don't want us to share your name, mailing address and email address, you can tell us that by clicking on "No" in the box at the time you register as a member on the Site or each time we request information from you or at other points. We sometimes share general, demographic, or aggregated (not personal) information with third parties about our user base, but that information does not include any Personal Information.

You will be deemed to have consented to the disclosure to, and use by, a subsequent owner or operator of the Sites, of any Personal Information contained in the NCSOFT database for such site, if NCSOFT or one of its companies assigns all of its rights and obligations regarding the use of your Personal Information at the time of a bankruptcy, merger, acquisition, sale of all or substantially all of NCSOFT's or game or other assets to a subsequent owner or operator, or similar event.

Please do not use your real name or the real name of another person when selecting a user name. Please note that your user name will be available to the Internet's general public while you participate in some services, like forums, chat rooms or message boards, so you should exercise discretion when using these services. Personal Information disclosed by you within our chat areas, instant message service, message boards, or during game play can be collected by other users of such services and may result in unsolicited messages.

We are not responsible for protecting such information that you may disclose to third parties through our services (e.g. sending your address to another user through the chat service). To the extent that you create a public profile that may be available to others on our sites and services, you are solely responsible for its content and accuracy at all times. To edit, change, or delete such information, follow the instructions on the web site.

**4\. Privacy protections for children**

In order to protect the privacy interests of younger Internet users, we do not allow children under the age of 18 to use our services without the consent of their parents. NCSOFT complies with the Children's Online Privacy Protection Act and all other applicable laws and regulations concerning children and the Internet.

**Children under the age of 13**

Because our Sites are not directed to children under the age of 13, NCSOFT does not provide memberships to persons under age 13. If you are under the age of 13, you may not create an account on the Site, you may not sign up for any subscription service or buy anything through our online store, and you are not eligible to enter any of our sweepstakes or promotions.

Except as may be required by law, NCSOFT will not knowingly collect, maintain, or disclose any personal information from children under the age of 13.

**Children between the ages of 13 and 18**

_If you are between the ages of 13 and 18, please let your parent or guardian know about this Privacy Policy and get his or her permission before you give us any of your personal identifiable information, before you use any of our message board, instant message or chat features, before you sign up for any subscription game services, and before you buy anything from our online store._

Don't post your real name on a website, forum or message board, and never tell anyone online anything private about yourself or your family, including your phone number and/or address. Use screen names and not real names at all times.

If you win a sweepstakes that has a prize, your parent or guardian will have to mail or fax us a signed note at the address or fax number listed in the rules for the specific contest that says it was OK for you to enter, and tells us they will accept the prize for you.

Some areas of the Site may have special rules for children under the age of 18. When you are in those areas, you must follow those rules.

**Information for Parents/Guardians**

If you are a parent or guardian who has discovered that your child has submitted his or her personal information without your permission or consent, NCSOFT will take reasonable steps to remove that information from the NCSOFT database at your request.

To request removal of your child's information, please send us an email at support@ncsoft.com and be sure to include in your message the same user name, password, and email address that your child submitted. If your child has used your credit card on our Sites without your permission, contact us immediately at support@ncsoft.com.

**California Minors**

We provide registered users the ability to post information on our Sites.  If you are a California resident who is under 18 and a registered user of our Sites and you are unable to remove content or information you posted in a public area of the Sites following the instructions provided on the Sites, you may request removal by using the contact information provided at the bottom of this Privacy Policy.  When requesting removal you must be specific about the information or content you want remove and provide the URL for each page on the Site where it is located so that we can locate it.

We are not required to remove any content or information that: (1) federal or state law requires us or a third party to maintain the content or information; (2) the content or information was not posted by you the registered user; (3) we anonymize the content or information so that you cannot be identified; (4) you don’t follow our instructions for removing or requesting removal; or (5) you received compensation or other consideration for providing the content or information.

**5\. The choices available to users regarding collection, use and distribution of the Personal Information**

Please note that if you provide any information on your own or directly to parties who provide service to our Sites or any other sites you encounter on the Internet (even if these sites are branded with our branding), different rules may apply to their use or disclosure of the Personal Information you disclose to them. We encourage you to investigate and ask questions before disclosing information to third parties.

**6\. Do not track signals (California Online Privacy Protection Act** )

(1) NCSOFT does not use or respond to "do not track" signals. Even if you select “Do Not Track” options provided by your browser, our Sites will still attempt to, and may be successful at, placing cookies, tracking identifiers, or other recording tools and collecting information from your browser.  You may still manage the settings on your browser or mobile device and delete and disable cookies and other tracking/recording tools. Doing so may impact your experience using our Sites and may make certain features and areas unavailable to you. We do not control tracking by third parties providers. See the section on “Third-party Advertisers and Analytics Providers” and review the privacy policies of each of the third party providers for more information on whether they honor the “Do Not Track” browser signal. For information about opting-out from Google Analytics tracking, see the links referenced in the “Third-party Advertisers and Analytics Providers” section above.

(2) NCSOFT does not sell or share Personal Information from NCSOFT players with third parties for those third parties’ direct marketing purposes.  California Civil Code Section 1798.83 permits California residents to request information from us concerning any disclosures of Personal Information we may have made in the prior calendar year to third parties for direct marketing purposes.  If you are a California resident and you wish to request information about our compliance with this law or our privacy practices, you may contact us by using the contact information at the bottom of this Privacy Policy.

**7\. How users can correct any inaccuracies in the Personal Information**

To review and update your Personal Information stored with NCSOFT, please [access your account](https://login.ncsoft.com/login).

If you change your mind and do not want to receive email from us and/or have us share your name and email address (or other personal information) with third parties, you may send an email to us at support@ncsoft.com.

If you choose to have your personal information removed from our active databases, we will do so within a reasonable time after your request and we will take reasonable steps to ensure that your personal data is not used (except as may be required by law) by NCSOFT after your notification to us.

**8\. What kind of security procedures we use to protect the loss, misuse, or alteration of your Personal Information under our control**

NCSOFT takes precautions to protect our users' information. When users submit sensitive information via our Sites, that information is protected both online and off-line.

We have established and maintain reasonable security procedures to protect the confidentiality, security and integrity of your personal information. We use encryption, Secure Socket Layers, and other technical measures (such as off-site backup, security testing, and password protection), and we implement off-line efforts to further protect this information, including limiting employee access to personal information and updating our employees regarding our security practices and privacy policies. Please recognize, however, that "perfect security" does not exist on the Internet.

If you have any questions about the security at our website or facilities, you can send an email to support@ncsoft.com.

**9\. Information for people in the European Union**

By consenting to this Privacy Policy, you confirm that your command and knowledge of English (or in some cases, French or German) is sufficient to understand the terms and conditions set forth herein.

For persons in European Union countries, as used in this Privacy Policy, terms such as "personal information" refer to "personal data" as defined by the UK Data Protection Act 1998 ("Act").  The terms "data controller" and "data processor" shall also be as defined in the Act.

We will not collect any personal data from you unless you provide it voluntarily by providing us with your freely given specific and informed consent. By using NCSOFT websites (including, without limitation, the Sites) or services, you agree that we may transfer your personal information outside the European Union in connection with the purposes stated in this Privacy Policy. Your personal data may be transferred to the United States (and/or other non-EU jurisdictions, as applicable).

If You are ordinarily resident in the European Union any reference to an age of 13 in shall be deemed a reference to the age in your home country, below which, children receive additional legal data protections afforded to younger minors.

**10\. Notices of changes to the Privacy Policy**

NCSOFT reserves the right to change this Privacy Policy at any time by notifying registered users via email of the existence of a new Policy and/or posting the new Policy on the Sites. All changes to the Privacy Policy will be effective when posted, and your continued use of any of the Sites, product or service after the posting will constitute your acceptance of, and agreement to be bound by, those changes.

If you feel that NCSOFT is not abiding by its posted privacy policy, you should contact us by email at privacy@ncsoft.com.

Last Updated: March 2016
